Guide to the Stanford University, Office for Religious Life, Records SC1057
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office for Religious Life, records
1973-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Office for Religious Life
SC1057
16.75 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
22937.6 megabyte(s)
The materials consist of administrative files, event programs and audiorecordings, publications, course materials, and videorecordings documenting activities of the Office for Religious Life.
Access to Collection
Open for research. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
The materials were transferred from the Office for Religious Life, 2011-2016.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in nine series: Series 1. Administration; Series 2. Events; Series 3. Fellowships; Series 4. Music; Series 5. Programs; Series 6. Publications; Series 7. Stanford Associated Religions; Series 8. Teaching; Series 9. Audiorecordings.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of administrative files, event programs and audiorecordings, publications, course materials, and videorecordings documenting activities of the Office for Religious Life.
Lectures.; Students -- Religious life.; Programs, church.; Sermons.; Stanford University. Office for Religious Life
- Administration
  - Register of the Rite of Marriage, 2011 Jun 4-2013 Mar 2 (Box 10)
  - Memorial services record, 1973 Sep 5-2000 Nov 21 (Box 10)
- Audio recordings, 1982-2004
  - Floyd Tompkins - Sermon at Dinkelspiel, 1989 Dec 10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Diana Akiyama: "Of Feeble Knees and Fearful Hearts." Dinkelspiel., 1989 Dec 17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Sunday service at Stanford Memorial Church. "Back to Basics." Louis Smedes., 1989 May 7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Diana Akiyama - Ordination at Stanford (Part 1), 1989 Apr 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Diana Akiyama - Ordination at Stanford (Part 2), 1989 Apr 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Robert Gregg - "Standing and Portable Truth.", 1988 Mar 13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Anthem: Salvation is Created (Tchesnokov). Ernie Young Sermon: "Giving Thanks" (11/20); Maurice Wiles Sermon: "Advent" (11/27), 1988 Nov 20, 27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Sandra Ragan-Kelly: "Christ the King" (11/24); Robert Morgan (12/1), 1985 Nov 24, Dec 1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Installation of the Dean, Rev. Robert Clark Gregg, 1987 Oct 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Daniel Cloete: "Perfect through Power?", 1985 May 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Barbara Brown Zikmund: "Worship: A Joy that Makes us Strong" (8/12); William Harter: "Back to the Land" (8/19), 1984 Aug 12, 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Frank Geer: "...to See the Stars" (1/16); Bernard Brown: "Our Rightful Minds" (1/30), 1983 Jan 16, 30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Frank Geer: "The Hardest Line" (7/24); Don Caughey: "Christian Materialism" (7/31), 1983 Jul 24, Jul 31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - David Read - Baccalaureate, 1983 Jun 11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ray Brown: "Gospel of John..." (3/14); Frank Geer: "Moment of Decision" (3/21), 1982 Mar 14, 1982 Mar 21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bishop Stuart: "A Tale of 2 Cities" (8/8); Don Caughey: "The Grace of Work" (9/5), 1982 Aug 8, 1982 Sep 5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Don Caughey: "Vocation of Marriage" (9/19); S.M. Ogden: "... As You Desire" (10/10), 1982 Sep 19, 1982 Oct 10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bishop Stuart "A tale of two cities" (8/8); Don Daughey "The grace of social work' (9/5), 1982 Aug 8, 1982 Sep 5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - [both sides unlabeled], 1977 Jun 11, 1977 June 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Thich Nhat Hanh, 1989 Apr 23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church Sunday service: Thich Nhat Hana "Dharma Talk", 1989 Apr 23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Rabbi Richard Block (10 a.m. service), 1989 Apr 30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ernle W.D. Young: "Authentic Discipleship", 1989 May 21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Diana Akiyama: "The Secret of Death" 10 am, third Sunday after Pentacost, 1989 Jun 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ernle Young: "Guess Who's Coming to Dinner?", 1989 Jun 11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ernle Young Sermon, 1989 Jun 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ernle Young Sermon: "An Essentially Non-Coercive God" (7/2/89); Diana Akiyama: "Who is My Neighbor?" (7/9/89), 1989 Jul 2, 1989 Jul 9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Sermons at Stanford Memorial Church: Dean R. Gregg. Prayer I: "Finding the Words" (7/23); Prayer II: "Body English" (7/30), 1989 Jul 23, 1989 Jul 30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Robert C. Gregg: "Shaken...Unshaken", 1989 Aug 27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Diana Akiyama: "When God Makes Your Face To Shine" (8/6); "When is the Kingdom?" (8/13); "Consideration for Discipleship" (9/10), 1989 Aug 6, 1989 Aug 13, 1989 Sep 10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ernle Young: "On Being Lost and Found" (9/3); "What Do We Really Want?" (9/16), 1989 Sep 3, 1989 Sep 16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Interfaith Service, 1989 Sep 24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Robert Gregg: "Fat Cat in Flames", 1989 Oct 1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Walter Breuggermann: "A Shameless Faith" (10/8); Rev. Floyd Thompkins, Jr. "The Captivity of a Queen" (10/15), 1989 Oct 8, 1989 Oct 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Richard Keeling: "Now, More Than Ever", 1989 Oct 29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Steve Roos: "Rapture Today!" Memorial Church at Dinkelspiel Auditorium, 1989 Nov 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Diana Akiyama: "Daring to Hope, Daring to Die", 1989 Nov 26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - "Faith, Philosophy, and Our Relationship to the Natural Environment" 10:00am Service, 1989 Jan 22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Faith, Philosophy, and Our Relationship to the Natural Environment" 10:00am Service, 1989 Jan 22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Easter Service at Stanford Memorial Church, 1989 Mar 26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Churc Service, 1989 Apr 2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Passion of the Christ," tape 1, 2004 Apr 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Passion of the Christ," tape 2, 2004 Apr 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Passion of the Christ," panel discussion at Cubberley Auditorium, tape 1, 2004 Apr 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Passion of the Christ," panel discussion at Cubberley Auditorium, tape 2, 2004 Apr 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Love and Life in SF," Mabel Teng & Rick Yuen, tape 1, 2004 Apr 27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Love and Life in SF," Mabel Teng & Rick Yuen, tape 2, 2004 Apr 27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
- Facilities, 2013-2015
- Fellowships, 2010-2015
- Music, 2010-2015
- Programs, 1990-2015
  - Baccalaureate, 2011-2015
    - Baccalaureate, 2014; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1U)
  - Cathlic Community Bulletin, 2010-2015
  - Compline, 2011-2015
  - Co-sponsored events, 2011-2015
  - Grief and loss, 2011-2015
  - Harry's Last Lecture for a Meaningful Life, 2014-2015
  - Robert W. Heyns Lecture, 1996-2015
  - Labyrinth, 2011-2015
  - Memorial Services, 2011-2015
  - Non-Office for Religious Life events
  - President's Higher Education Community Service Challenge, 2013-2015
  - Special services, 2011-2015
  - Students Organizing Unique Liturgical Settings (SOULS), 2014
  - What Matters to Me & Why, 2002-2015
    - Pizzo, Philip, Dean of the School of Medicine, 2002 Nov 6; 1 audiocassette(s)
    - Carstensen, Laura, 2005 Jan 12; 11.1; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.1U)
    - Berger, Jonathan, 2005 Dec; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
    - Ross, Janice, 2006 May 17; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
    - Everett, Shirley, 2006 Oct 25; 11.2; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.2U)
    - Matson, Pamela, 2006 Nov 8; 11.3; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.3U)
    - Quickley, Jerry, 2007 Feb 7; 11.4; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.4U)
    - Strober, Myra, 2007 Apr 18; 11.5; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.5U)
    - Shachter, Ross D., 2007 May 16; 11.6; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.6U)
    - Reich, Rob, 2007 Oct 24; 11.7; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.7U)
    - Bilfield, Jenny, 2007 Nov 7; 11.8; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.8U)
    - Shaw, Richard, 2007 Jan 17; 11.9; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.9U)
    - Diamond, Larry, 2008 Jan 23; 11.10; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.10U)
    - Simms, Winona, 2008 Feb 20; 11.11; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.11U)
    - Hayes, Aleta, 2008 Apr 9; 11.12; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.12U)
    - Siegel, Bob, 2009 Jan 21; 11.13; 1 computer file(s) (wav) (Box 11.13U)
    - Golder, Deborah, Associate Vice Provost for Student Affairs and Dean of Residential Education, 2010 Feb 24; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
    - Rakove, Jack, William Robertson Coe Professor of History and American Studies and professor of political science and (by courtesy) law at Stanford, 2010 Apr 28; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
    - Murray, Anne Firth, Consulting Professor in Human Biology, 2010 May 12; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
    - Karlan (audio), 2011 Apr 27; 1 computer file(s) (ncd)
    - Karlan (flyer), 2011 Apr 27; 1 computer file(s) (pdf)
    - Yalom, Irving (audio), 2011 May 4; 1 computer file(s) (ncd)
    - Yalom, Irving (flyer), 2011 May 4; 1 computer file(s) (pdf)
    - Edelman, Marian Wright, 2011 Nov 30; 11.14; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 11.14U)
  - University Public Worship, 1990-2015
    - 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 2)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 3)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 5)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 6)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 7)
    - 2008-2009 (Box 8)
    - 2010-2011 (Box 9)
- Publications, 2010-2015
- Stanford Associated Religions, 2010-2011
- Teaching, 2011-2015
- Additional records, Accession ARCH-2015-110
  - Register of the Rite of Marriage, 2011 Jun 4-2013 Mar 2
  - BJ Overbaugh Memorial, 1998 Apr 2; 1_01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Satan and His Angels: A Talk by Elaine Pagels, 1996 May 23; 1_02; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Philip Pizzo, Dean of the School of Medicine, 2002 Nov 6; 1_03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Harry's Last Lecture On a Meaningful Life: Garry Trudeau, 2014 Apr 28; 1_04; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Baccalaureate, 2013; 1_05; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Deborah Golder, 2010 Feb 24; 1_06; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Jack Rakove, 2010 Apr 28; 1_07; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Anne Firth Murray, 2010 May 12; 1_08; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why?, 2009 James Steyer; 1_09; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Centennial Chat: Betsy Koester (Wedding Coordinator), 2003 Oct 16; 1_10; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Centennial Chat: Leslie Bone (Conservator at Memorial Church, co-author "Glory of Angels", 2003 Dec 9; 1_11; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Tour Susan #2, 2003 Jan 31; 1_12; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Tour Susan Christiansen #1, 2003 Jan 31; 1_13; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Palo Alto Alumni Tour, 2003 Jan 23; 1_14; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Shirley Everett, 2006 Oct 25; 1_15; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Janice Ross, 2006 May 17; 1_16; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Jonathan Berger, 2005 Dec 7; 1_17; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - What Matters to Me and Why? Laura Carstensen, 2005 Jan 12; 1_18; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Conversation with Paco Peña and Scotty Mclennan, 2004 Jan 29; 1_19; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - A Celebration of the Life of Jacques Mequet Littlefield, 2009 Mar 2; 1_20; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - A Celebration of the Life of George D. Gulevich, MD, 2009 May 28; 1_21; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - SAR Meeting, 2006 Jan 19; 1_22; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Centennial Chat: Robert Huw Morgan, University Organist, 2003 Nov 12; 1_23; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
- Additional records, Accession ARCH-2015-165
  - Register of the Rite of Marriage, 2013 Feb 2-2014 Oct 4 (Box 1)
  - Harry's Last Lecture--What Matters to Me & Why
    - Winfrey, Oprah, 2015 Apr 20; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd)
- Additional records, Accession ARCH-2016-125
  - Stanford University Baccalaureate, 2016-06-11; 1.1; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Contemplation by Design Inner Strength and Kindness: Practices for a Wise Life with Jack Kornfield Memorial Church, 2015-11-10; 1.2; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Highlights from Letter from a Birmingham Jail Anna Deavere Smith with Robert McDuffie - violin Anne Epperson - piano Memorial Church, 2015-10-21; 1.3 (Box 1)
- Additional records, Accession ARCH-2017-007
  - Register of the Rite of Marriage, 2014 Oct 4-2016 Sep 3 (Box 1)
- Additional records, Accession ARCH-2017-069
  - Ecumenical Good Friday Service program, 2016-3-25 (Box 1)
- Additional records, Accession ARCH-2017-115
  - Order of Service, 2016 Oct 23 (Box 1)